Donald Barthelme, Sr. Architectural Papers, 1924-1997
University of Houston Libraries
- Barthelme Personal Library
  - Knoll International. Knoll International Textile Price List 1977/78. New York: Knoll International, 1977.
  - Knoll Associates. Knoll Index of Contemporary Design. NewYork: Knoll Associates, 1954.
  - Le Corbusier. Le Corbusier and Pierre Jeanneret: Oeuvre Complete 1934-1938. Zurich: Dr. H. Girsberger, 1939.
  - Linton, Ralph and Paul S. Wingert. Arts of the South Seas. New York: Museum of Modem Art, 1946.
  - Lockwood, E.H. A Book of Curves. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1961.
  - Lootens, J. Ghislain. Lootens on Photographic Enlarging and Print Quality. Baltimore: Fleet-McGinley, 1944.
  - Mindlin, Henrique E. Modern Architecture in Brazil. New York: Reinhold, 1956.
  - Montagu, Ashley. The Biosocial Nature of Man. New York: Grove Press, 1956.
  - National Lumber Manufacturers Association. Wood Structural Design Data. vol. I. Washington, D.C.: National Lumber Manufacturers Association, 1941.
  - Neutra, Richard. Survival Through Design. New York: Oxford University Press, 1954.
  - Peter, John.. Aluminum in Modern Architecture. 2 vols. Louisville: Reynolds Metals Co., 1956.
  - Ramsey, Charles George, and Harold Reeve Sleeper. Architectural Graphic Standards for Architects, Engineers, Decorators, Builders, and Draftmen. New York: Wiley, 1932.
  - Rice University. 10 Designs/Community Colleges. Houston: Rice University School of Architecture, 1962.
  - Roth, Alfred. The New Architecture: Examined on 20 Examples. Zurich: Girsberger, 1940.
  - Rudofsky, Bernard. The Prodigious Builders. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1977.
  - Saarinen, Eliel. Search For Form: A Fundamental Approach to Art. New York: Reinhard, 1948.
  - Schroeder, Francis de N. Anatomy for Interior Designers and How to Talk to a Client. New York: Whitney Publications, 1948.
  - Simon Enterprises. The Reston Story. Fairfax, Virginia: Victor Weingarten Co., undated
  - Simonds, John Ormsbee. Landscape Architecture: The Shaping of Man's Natural Environment. New York: McGraw-Hill. 1961.
  - Sleeper, Harold Reeve. Architectural Specifications. New York: Wiley, 1940.
  - Smith, G. E. Kidder. Sweden Builds: Its Modern Architecture and Land Policy Background, Development and Contribution. New York and Stockholm: Albert Bonnier, 1950.
  - Smith, G. E. Kidder. Switzerland Builds: Its Native and Modern Architecture. New York and Stockholm: Albert Bonnier, 1950.
  - Soby, James Thrall, and Dorothy C. Miller. Romantic Painting in America. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1943.
  - Soby, James Thrall. Contemporary Painters. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1948.
  - Sommer, Robert. Personal Space. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1969.
  - University of Texas School of Architecture. Image 5-6. Austin: University of Texas, 1969(2 copies).
  - Vitruvius. The Ten Books on Architecture.. New York: Dover, 1960.
  - Wheeler, Monroe. Modern Drawings. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1944.
  - Yoshida, Tetsuro. Das Japanische Wohnhaus. Berlin: Wasmuth, 1935.
  - Yoshida, Tetsuro. The Japanese House and Garden. New York: Praeger, 1956.
  - Zahle, Erik. A Treasury of Scandinavian Design. New York: Golden Press, 1961